(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're gonna
have a fun, funny lesson.
- That's right, so I think
this lesson's gonna be
a little bit different than
most of our lessons, right?
- Right, today we're
gonna be looking at jokes,
which is a very important
part of English speaking culture.
- Yeah, so we're actually,
we're gonna teach you
a few pretty hilarious jokes, but we're
also gonna teach you some language related
to jokes, funny things,
and that sort of stuff.
- All right, so in order
for us to understand
a little bit better, the jokes
that we're gonna be looking at,
why don't we take a look
at vocabulary preview?
- Very vocabulary preview.
- Two of these words
you'll hear in the dialogue,
but one you won't, but
you still need to know
this word so you can
understand the jokes.
- All right, so the word that we're talking
about is not really a word, it's a sound.
- Yeah, move.
- Move.
- So, move is the sound that cows make.
- That's right, M-O-O.
- Right, they go, move.
- Very nice, Marco.
- I could do a good cow.
- Yep, all right, so we all know
now that that's what cows say.
- Exactly, so it's gonna be
important for the joke, you'll see why.
- Okay, now another word that
you need to understand is a dam.
- So a dam.
- A dam.
- A dam is like a big wall, right?
- Well, it's a wall in water that
stops the river from flowing.
- Okay, so usually you build dams in
rivers and then the water can pass or not.
- Yeah, it's something that you
used to generate electricity, right?
- Very good.
- But there's another
word that sounds exactly
the same way, but it's
just built a little differently.
- That's right, and we might
hear someone say, "Oh, dam!
"
- And that's an interjection,
which basically means.
- Oh no, that's terrible.
- Yeah, dam, I can say
dam, I forgot my keys.
- Dam, we're late for the movie.
- Okay, so it's an interesting interjection
and we'll also see it in one of our jokes.
And now let's move on to our last word.
- Nostrils.
- Okay, nostrils.
- So a nostril or your nostrils?
- The two holes in your nose.
- Right, you breathe through your nostrils.
- All right, so now that we've taken a look
at these three words, why don't we
listen to our comedian for the first time
and then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more.
(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, and
welcome to Open Mike Knight.
You're in for a real treat as we've got a
lot of great comics here with us tonight.
First up, we have a very funny man
coming straight from the state of Montana.
- Robert Hicks.
- Thank you everyone.
Well, what a lovely crowd.
You know, there's nothing I
love better than stand up comedy.
You know, I've been working
on my routine for months now
and I've got some real
singers for you tonight.
Let's start out with some short jokes.
How about that?
Where do you find a one-legged dog?
(dramatic music)
Where you left it?
Get it?
Anyways, what do you
call a sheep with no legs?
(dramatic music) The cloud.
(dramatic music)
What's up crowd?
All right, now you're gonna love this joke.
It's hilarious.
What do cows do for entertainment?
They rent movies, movies.
(dramatic music)
Okay, okay, okay, we've got a few hecklers
in the audience but this one is good.
What does a fish say
when it runs into a wall?
(dramatic music) Damn!
(dramatic music)
Okay, okay, okay, last one.
Why do gorillas have big nostrils?
(dramatic music)
'Cause they got big fingers.
Thanks everyone, that was my time.
(dramatic music)
Okay, so some pretty hilarious jokes, huh?
I don't think the crowd really
enjoyed them all that much.
Okay, well maybe I'm just
a fan of really terrible jokes.
Well, they were pretty funny,
but I guess the crowd just didn't
appreciate his sense of humor.
But you know what, they did use
quite a lot of really interesting language.
So why don't we look at that
now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
On language takeaway,
we're gonna be looking
at six words today,
so let's get started.
The announcer welcomed everyone
and said that it's open mic night.
Open mic night.
So an open mic night.
Okay, well we know mic is
short for microphone, right?
Now an open mic night is a chance
where anyone can come up
and talk into the microphone.
So you can come up and sing or you can
tell jokes, you can do anything basically.
Yeah.
All right, open mic night.
So it's not for professionals,
but for people who maybe
want to be professionals.
Right, amateurs.
So it was open mic night and he said
they had a lot of great comics there.
So comics, a comic, a comic.
So basically a comic is a person that
makes a living by making people laugh.
Yeah, someone who stands
up on stage and tells jokes.
All right, would you say a
clown is kind of like a comic?
No, the difference.
A comic doesn't wear a red
nose and a crazy costume.
Yeah.
All right, yeah, 'cause I hate clowns.
We do know that about you.
All right, so a comic.
And what comics do is they
perform a standup comedy.
Standup comedy.
Okay, so standup comedy is really
exactly what its name suggests, right?
Right, you stand up in front of an audience
and you tell jokes or you make them laugh.
Yeah, tell funny stories.
It's a very popular form of entertainment
in the United States and the UK.
That's right.
And I think we'll talk a little bit more
about that at the end of the lesson,
but why don't we move on to
our next word, which is routine.
A routine.
So the guy says I've been
working on my routine.
So what does he mean by his routine?
Well, I guess a routine is
like a series or a collection
of jokes or maybe movements
that you use in a performance.
All right, a routine.
So you can talk about a dance routine.
Or in this case, a comedy routine.
So the series of jokes he's gonna tell.
That's right, that he practices
again and again and again.
All right, and in his routine, he said he's
got a lot of zingers, zingers, a zinger.
So what's a zinger?
Basically a zinger is like a
strong, maybe a little bit rude joke.
Yeah, but like a kind
of a one-line joke, right?
Right, exactly.
Yeah.
And the people that were in the crowd and
they were booing and they were like boo.
Those we call hecklers.
Exactly, and that's
our last word, a heckler.
A heckler, heckler is, so let's
listen to some hecklers in action.
(dramatic music)
All right, well, I think
that's pretty clear.
Those are definitely hecklers.
Right, they're very annoying.
So now that we've finished
looking at all the words
that are related to
comedy and performances,
let's take a look at the
jokes now in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
Okay, well, we're not really
focusing on new phrases
for you here, but we thought
it would be helpful to talk a
little bit about the jokes to
help you understand them, right?
'Cause they are, well,
I think pretty funny.
Yeah, they're pretty funny, but maybe
sometimes they're kind of hard to understand.
So why don't we start with the first joke?
So you said, where do
you find a one-legged dog?
So what's a one-legged dog?
Basically it's a dog that has one leg.
Okay, and the pronunciation
here is important, right?
One-legged.
Not one-legged.
No.
One-legged.
So you can say one-legged
dog, a two-legged dog,
or three-legged dog.
Six-legged dog?
A six-legged spider,
maybe lost two legs in a war.
Oh, dear.
Okay, so the dog obviously
didn't go anywhere,
and so that's why you
find it where you left it.
Exactly.
So that's why it's kind of funny.
Okay.
All right, so then he said, what
do you call a sheep with no legs?
I don't know.
A cloud, basically because
sheep are fluffy and they're white,
so if you take away their
legs, they look like a little cloud.
Boom.
All right, let's look at the next one.
He asked, what do cows
do for entertainment?
And then the answer was, they rent movies.
Exactly.
So it's kind of funny because
he's relating this word movies
with the sound that
cows make, which is moo.
Right, and actually,
there are a million jokes
in English following
the same pattern, right?
Yeah, exactly.
So I'm sure you can find a lot more of
them, and you can share them with us.
Now, my personal
favorite joke is the guy says,
what does a fish say
when it runs into a wall?
So to run into a wall,
basically to crash against a wall.
Yep.
So what does a fish say?
Damn.
So why is this funny?
Why does it say damn?
Well, 'cause if you're a
person and you run into a wall,
damn, like, you know,
just like, oh no, yeah.
But a fish is swimming under the water,
and like we saw, a dam is
actually like a wall in the water.
So he's saying like, oh, a wall.
Yeah, yeah, so that, I like that one.
All right, the last one was pretty good.
Why do gorillas have big nostrils?
Okay, so the big holes in their nose.
Right, and basically it's
because they have big fingers.
So they can put their fingers in the nose?
Yeah, exactly.
If the gorilla didn't have big nostrils,
he wouldn't be able to pick his nose.
Maybe he'd have to use a stick.
Yeah, but that wouldn't be convincing, see?
All right.
So that's why those jokes are funny.
They're very short jokes.
Some, of course, some of
them are not actually really funny.
But it's just a little bit of a
taste of short American jokes.
Okay, well, I think we need to
hear them one more time in context.
So you can all know how funny
or maybe not so funny they are.
Hello, everyone, and
welcome to Open Mike Knight.
You're in for a real treat as we've got a
lot of great comics here with us tonight.
First up, we have a very funny man
coming straight from the state of Montana.
Robert Pix.
Thank you, everyone.
Well, what a lovely crowd.
You know, there's nothing I
love better than stand-up comedy.
You know, I've been
working on my routine for
months now, and I've got
some real singers for you tonight.
Let's start out with some short jokes.
How about that?
Where do you find a one-legged dog?
Where you left it.
Get it?
Mmm.
Anyways, what do you
call a sheep with no legs?
A cloud.
All right.
Now you're going to love this joke.
It's hilarious.
What do cows do for entertainment?
They read movies, movies, movies.
Okay, okay, okay, we've got a few hecklers
in the audience, but this one is good.
But there's a fish say
when it runs into a wall.
Damn!
Okay, okay, okay, last one.
Why do gorillas have big nostrils?
They got big fingers.
Now if you have any
good jokes of your own,
why don't you come to our
website and tell us about them?
Right.
Come to EnglishPod.com.
Share with us any jokes.
Of course, they have to be clean.
Don't come with me.
No, no squares.
There's no swearing in the jokes.
Yep.
All right.
So we'll see you guys there.
And until next time.
Thanks for listening and goodbye.
Bye.